README.md 8/15/2019

Nicholas Barnes

I'm a fresh full stack developer and experienced artist equipped with strong ideation and the processes to build anything.

I have just finished studying at Makers Academy, an intensive developer acceleration course.

I'm looking for my first developer role in an environment that supports learning and lets creativity flourish.

Skills

Quick on the uptake

The tools to create a project are just that. The why is the root of any endeavour.

Diving into coding was motivated by a need to have a way to take thoughts forward and realise them in the world. I'm consistently astonished by the scope of problems code can be applied to. As it will enable me to build the things I want to see, I value it highly and am actively learning to apply it.

I'm driven by interesting concepts. For my final project at Makers, I couldn't shake the urge to give people a unique experience. To this end, I designed a maze generating algorithm to provide a new level every time the game is played. This was written in C# (a language I hadn't really used before the project), in one day.

For any situation, I'm confident I can get to grips with the required technologies.

Lateral thinking

I'm never short of ideas, and I take great joy in making connections to solve problems.

I always find satisfaction in the elegant solution, the cleanest route to the resolution. On the recent maze project it would have taken a day to write the treasure-placing algorithm we needed. Instead, I found how we had similarities in our current logic, and implemented the solution in less than ten lines.

As an animator there were constant novel challenges to face. When asked to cut hundreds of paper tiles for a geometric pattern on a set and place them by hand, I sourced a laser-cutter and removed the negative space from several layers of colour to let the shapes through. This gave us perfect symmetry, and saved days of labour.

There is always a solution, and a way to improve it.

Projects

Project	Description	Timeframe	Technologies
Mandala- coaster	Personal project, a virtual reality pattern generator	7 days	Unity, C#, GearVR
Hide and Go Beetroot	Final team project at Makers, a virtual reality maze game	9 days	Unity, C#, GearVR

README.md 8/15/2019

Project	Description	Timeframe	Technologies
SpaceBook	Team project imitating Facebook	9 days	Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Capybara, CSS, Travis
MakersBnB	Team project imitating AirBnB	5 days	Ruby, Rspec, Sinatra, PostgrsQL, Datamapper

Education

Makers Academy (April to July 2019)

A 16-week intensive development bootcamp, with a focus on:

- Pair programming and emotional intelligence
- OOP best practices
- Test Driven Development
- Agile development process and XP values
- Ruby, Sinatra, Rails, JavaScript
- RSpec, Capybara, Jasmine
- · Git workflow
- Self-directed learning
- Code reviews

Blog of my Makers journey

Manchester School of Art (2009 to 2012)

- BAHons Illustration with Animation
- 1st
- Specialised in experimental visual communication and narrative
- Participated in drawing exhibitions and live drawing at street festivals
- The course was quite conceptual in its approach, so it was up to me to teach myself the creative softwares I needed (Blender, Adobe suite, Ableton).

Experience

Avalon English (November 2017 to December 2018) English teacher

I knew I wanted to attend some kind of coding bootcamp, and that would require funding. After some research, TEFL sounded like a solid option. With zero teaching experience I secured a position, flew across the world, and ended up the student's favourite teacher. With careful budgeting I knew I would have enough to apply to Makers Academy after a year, so I completed my contract and headed to London.

Illustrated journal of a year in South Korea

Freelance animator (2012 to 2017) Direction, storyboarding, animating

Pitching on music videos meant I had to quickly visualise and communicate the essence of the project, and then find the most effective way to execute. This including researching aesthetics, tools, and techniques.

README.md 8/15/2019

Highlight - Having a film of mine screened at Manchester Gallery, scored by a live seventeen piece orchestra.

Animation portfolio

Passions

I've always got a myriad unfinished projects on the go in as many discipines as necessary to satisfy whichever particular expressive urge I'm feeling. These include but aren't limited to:

- Writing journals, poetry, outlines for games
- Interactive art sketches for android and command line
- Drawing
- Calligraphy
- Digital sculpture

Beyond creative output I'm an avid consumer of art and media, and I swim, meditate and practice yoga.

Contact:

email